In this video, we will be reviewing how to use the automate pricing file to assign SKUs
to a re-pricing rule or stop re-pricing in a bulk upload process.
We'll also cover some helpful tips so you can make the most of using the automate pricing
file.
Let's get started.
Automate pricing saves you time and effort by adjusting prices based on the rules that
you set.
After you've created a pricing rule in the automate pricing tool in Seller Central, you
can either assign SKUs to that rule in the tool up to 50 SKUs per time, or use the automate
pricing file for bulk uploads.
The automate pricing file gives you greater flexibility when managing a large catalog
by letting you assign a rule to thousands of SKUs at a time.
There are six steps to assigning SKUs to a rule using the automate pricing file.
Before we walk you through the process in detail, let's look at an overview of each step.
Step 1.
Download the automate pricing file.
Step 2.
Select the SKUs in the country you want to assign to a pricing rule.
Step 3.
Set a minimum price so your price stays above the minimum price you set.
Step 4.
Enter the rule you wish to re-price in the rule name column.
Step 5.
Enter start or stop depending on whether you wish to start re-pricing with a rule or stop
re-pricing and remove the SKU from the rule.
And finally, step 6.
Upload the template into Seller Central.
Now that you have the steps, let's walk you through them with some examples.
To access the automate pricing file, log in to Seller Central and select automate pricing
from the pricing tab.
Select edit SKUs on the predefined pricing rule and select manage SKUs via file upload,
which will take you to the download center of automate pricing.
Select the store of the offers that you want to manage.
You can download a blank automate pricing file or a file that has your information pre-filled.
We will walk you through both types of files.
For now, let's select the blank file and click on download automate pricing file.
Once the file downloads, you can review the file instructions, data definitions, and a
sample of a completed file.
Next, select the SKUs you want to start re-pricing.
For our example, we'll enter just three SKUs.
For each SKU, you'll need to enter a minimum price to ensure your re-pricing rules don't
send your price below the minimum price you want.
While optional, you can also enter a maximum price to ensure your price stays below it.
If you don't enter a maximum price, automate pricing will protect customer trust on your
behalf by ensuring that your offers are not priced significantly higher than recent prices,
so that your offers remain eligible to become the featured offer.
Then enter the country and currency code where the offer is active.
Now, enter the exact name of the re-pricing rule you want to assign.
To do this, just copy and paste the name from the automate pricing tool.
Finally, enter start or stop in the rule action field.
If you select start, the SKU will start re-pricing using the rule you have specified.
If you select stop, the SKU will stop re-pricing.
If you choose to stop re-pricing, you don't need to enter a rule name, minimum price, maximum
price, or currency code.
Download a pre-populated file to save the time and effort needed to enter the required
information for each SKU.
To access the pre-populated automate pricing file, go to the download center of automate
pricing.
Select the pre-populated file.
At this time, you can only filter for the SKUs that are not enrolled in the automate pricing
tool sorted by sales rank.
Choose the number of SKUs you want to download.
The options are 500, 5000, or 15,000 SKUs.
Select the request automate pricing file.
You can monitor the status of the download in the bottom section.
Click on refresh to get the latest status.
After the request is complete, click on the download link.
The SKU, item name, country, country code, and rule action will already be filled out
for you.
In addition, if you've already set a minimum and maximum price, those fields will also
be filled in.
The pre-populated file also contains your current offer price.
featured offer price and the lowest price at the time of download, to help you set or update
your minimum and maximum prices.
Enter the exact name of the re-pricing rule you want to use.
You can copy and paste the name from the automate pricing tool.
It's a good idea to review your SKUs to make sure that the right SKUs have been assigned
to the rules you want, with the correct minimum and maximum prices, optional.
If all the information looks good, save your file as a UTF-8 tab delimited text file.
For information on saving the file in UTF-8 format, please refer to the instructions tab
in the download template.
After you have saved the file, using UTF-8 encoding format, go back to the Manage SKUs
in bulk via download and upload files screen.
Click upload center.
Click on choose file to identify and select your file.
Then, click on the upload automate pricing file.
In the monitor automate pricing file upload status section, you can get the latest status
on the processing of your file by clicking on the refresh button.
As your SKUs process, they will begin re-pricing.
After the file is processed, you can download the processing report to see the result of
each SKU.
Thanks for watching Automate Pricing in Action!
Happy selling!